[Music]
as noted in editorial and the Journal of
American Medical Association on
plant-based meat
Alternatives just looking at the
nutrition facts info of a regular burger
versus beyond meat or the impossible
Burger you wouldn't necessarily be able
to predict the health consequences
without further studies but we've had
plan based meat alternatives for over a
century I mean who wouldn't want a can
of good eaten protos it is after all the
modern vegetable meat Patent filed by Dr
John Harvey Kellogg in
1899 of course products such as tofu and
Tempe existed in Asia for centuries but
you know I think of those as separate
foods in their own right as opposed to
products intentionally designed to mimic
the The Taste and texture of meat with
such a rich history hearkening back to
the days of past the protina you'd think
there'd be some studies of consumers and
indeed there are for example girls who
eat meat may start their periods 6
months earlier than girls who don't is
it just because they're eating lots of
uh protein and fat evidently not because
girls who instead are eating meat
analoges like you know veggie burgers
and veggie dogs are able to Del delay
menstruation by 9 months of course it's
hard to tease out how much of that is
just from avoiding the meat but compared
with girls who eat meat just a few times
a week those who ate meat a few times a
day at a significantly early age of
first menstration which also may help
provide an explanation for why childhood
meat consumption is linked to breast
cancer later in life since the earlier
you start your period the higher your
lifetime risk now obesity itself May
contribute to the early onset of puberty
and girls so I mean that could be
another Factor Studies have suggested
vegetarian children tend to be leaner
than nonvegetarian children they aren't
smaller in general though vegetarian
boys and girls May measure up to be
about an inch taller than their
classmates they just aren't as wide so
the fact that girls who eat plant-based
Meats may be less likely to suffer from
premature puberty May in part be because
they were leaner indeed childhood
obesity research found meat consumption
seemed to double the odds of school
children becoming overweight compared to
the consumption of plant-based meat now
whole plant food sources of protein such
as beans did even better though
associated with cutting in half the odds
of kids becoming overweight so that's
why I consider these kinds of
plant-based Meats more of a useful
stepping stone towards a healthier diet
rather than the endgame idea deal the
same amount of protein in a bean burrito
would be better in nearly every
way simil in terms of hip fracture risk
in the Adventist 2 study following tens
of thousands of men and women for years
daily intake of plant-based Meats appear
to reduce the risk of hip fracture by
nearly half but daily legum intake beans
split bees chickp and lentils may drop
risk of hip fracture by even more nearly
2/3
[Music]